TEJAS WALIA

India | Mobile: +91-98103-20754 | Email: Walia.tejas@gmail.com

PROFILE SUMMARY

A versatile professional holding **more than four years** of experience in the **IT Industry** playing the Senior Administrator role. Excellence in Cloud Management and Automation for diligently developing private and hybrid cloud use cases employing Orchestrator (vRO), vRealize Automation (vRA) and Azure Terraform Development. Proficient in developing vRO workflows for integration with third-party tools by using REST API calls and PowerShell scripting capabilities. Articulate communicator with outstanding analytical abilities, problem-solving, decision-making and interpersonal skills

NOTEWORTHY ACHIEVEMENTS/HIGHLIGHTS

- Systematically delivered Complex automation use cases utilizing vRealize Orchestrator, vRealize Automation and Terraform, comprising of F5, Database, Linux, Active Directory, SCCM, backup, oracle, SQL, IIS, DNS, User Management Tasks
- Azure and vSphere development using terraform

SKILLS

•	Cloud Management
•	Azure Development

- Patch ManagementRequirement Gathering
- Agent Onboarding

• Configuration Management

- Server Management
- User Management
- Remediation Management
- Build Procedure Documenting
- Validation Management
- Integrations Documentation
- Third-party Integration
- Terraform Development
- Tool Configuration

TECHNICAL SKILLS

VMware vRealize Orchestrator (v7.2 - v7.5)
Scripting:
JavaScript, PowerShell (v3.0, v5.0),YAML (v1.2), Python
NEtwork:
NSX
Jenkins, GitHub

Cloud Automation:
 Cloud Technology:
 VRealize Automation (v7.3 - v7.5)
 VMware, vSphere, Azure, AWS

Operating System: MS Windows (v2012, v2016), Linux (RHEL 7.2, 7.5)

Database: MS SQL (2012, 2016)
Management Tools: MS Office, Jira

• ITSM: Service Now (London, Jakarta)

• CM Tools: SCCM (2012, B 1802), Ansible (v2.7), Terraform

Software Methodology: Scrum

CERTIFICATION & TRAINING

- Terraform Certified Associate | VMware Certified Professional 7 Cloud Management and Automation
- Certified on VCP 2021 | Certified on Azure Administrator AZ-104

WORK EXPERIENCE

Organization	Designation	Duration
Medline Industries	Medline Industries	Nov 2021 - Till Date
Cloudaeon Technology Ltd.	Automation Engineer	Jan 2021 - Oct 2021
HCL Technologies Ltd.	Senior Analyst	Jul 2017 - Dec 2020

Overall Responsibilities

- Actively associating with Cloud Management and Automation practise team for developing private and hybrid cloud use cases employing Orchestrator (vRO) and vRealize Automation (vRA)
- Acting significantly for leveraging Life Cycle Extensibility delivering complicated vRAuse-cases encompassing custom properties, entitlements and other customization capabilities of vRealize Automation
- Significantly developing
 - use cases for day two operations, namely patch management and software installations employing configuration management tools, such as Ansible and SCCM, backup as a service utilizing backup tools, namely Commvault, Networker for vRA managed machines applying Event Broker Service of vRA and vRO scripting capabilities
 - o vRO workflows for integration with third-party tools, like Service Now, Commvault, Azure, SCCM, Puppet, Ansible by utilizing REST API calls and PowerShell scripting capabilities
 - o blueprint where the request is processed with the NSX security feature and attained the use case via VRO
- Appropriately integrating

- F5 load balancer with vRO to render on-demand load balancing for various tiers of a multi-tier deployment
- IPAM providers, namely Infoblox, Solar Winds to produce out of the box IP allocation & DNS registration utilizing vRO workflows
- Associating on 300+ complex Runbook and use case development comprising of infra task of storage, Database, Linux Active directory, windows tasks, VMware, backup, oracle, SQL, IIS, Networking tasks, DNS, Administrator Tasks, Server Management, User Management Tasks, Decommissioning
- Managing Azure day-to-day tasks for the setup of VM and containers
- Setup Azure infra with Terraform | Setup vSphere infra with Terraform
- Accomplishing integration with third-party ITSM tools, like ServiceNow (SNOW), using REST API calls via vRO workflows

PROJECT DETAILS

CMP Platform Deployment | Cloud Developer | Customer: Energy Infrastructure Company

Team Size - Three (Part of the team)

- Organized to deploy vRealize Automation 7.4 and Orchestrator following client specifications
- Appropriately configured the tool to match functional requirements
- Carefully developed
 - o blueprints for consumption and designed custom form for providing "Decision Driven" automated provisioning of workloads for end-user consumption
 - o the entire decommissioning process for the VRA/vCenter Machines correspondingly
- Carried out various integrations with CM (Ansible) SCCM for deploying Applications on the newly provisioned workloads
- Systematically integrated 3rd party toolsets, in naming a few, SNOW, PUPPET, AD, SCCM, SCOM, Infoblox IPAM for POST
 provisioning activities following the compliance standards | Generated a disk SCSI logic for the newly furnished machines via vRA
- Significantly designed set tags workflows for employing the tags on VM on the vCenter
- Precisely documenting the build procedure and SOP for the deployed tool
- Handled the patching process for the freshly equipped machines | Performed the remediation for seven use cases on 6000 servers

IaaS POD Automation & CMP Platform Deployment | Cloud Developer | Customer: Pharmaceutical

Team Size - Five (Part of the team)

- Implemented vRealize Automation 7.6 and Orchestrator complied with client specifications.
- Developed end-to-end
 - o automation flow for the IT Infrastructure to decrease the build cycle & render automated delivery of compliant workloads
 - o end-to-end Backup workflow for the virtual machine deployed via vRA or VCENTER
- Skillfully created
 - o 7 IaaS Multi-Machine application patterned blueprints & XaaS blueprints for the Service Catalog besides single machine blueprints | Automation flow for the "Decision Driven Provisioning" of the workloads via XaaS Blueprints
 - o Subscriptions and vRO workflows for Application, Web and DB tier for accomplishing POST equipping tasks (Agent installation, SQL installation, App Deployment) on the freshly deployed app-centric workloads
 - o vRO Automation flows for manual efforts Day 2 operations, namely ADD/Increase Disk, Memory, vCPUs, changing lease etc. and exhibited as a catalogue Item for end-user consumption within Self-service portal
- Carried out the decommissioning process for the VM's deployed via vRA and VCENTER

CMP Service Provider | Cloud Developer | Customer: Internal Clientele

Team Size - Five (Part of the team)

- Incorporated the vRealize Automation 8.4 per client specifications
- Developed vRO Workflows for accomplishing different integrations with CM(Ansible), ITSM (Service Now), Database (SQL 2012,2016), Logging & Monitoring (vRLI, Wavefront,vROPS), Vulnerability Scanning (Rapid7) toolset for deploying Applications on the freshly furnished workloads
- Designed network automation workflow for dynamic Security Tagging for the established machines, as per its Business Unit, Application and Environment

Azure Infra Setup using Terraform | Cloud Developer | Customer: Health Care | Team Size - Five (Part of the team)

Team Size - Five (Part of the team)

- Conducted requirement gathering meetings with different teams for collecting details to set up the Infra
- Set up Modules for Terraform to provision machines and set up the infra with network configuration
- Utilized Cloud-Init approach for post provisioning task and using user data for post –provisioning task

EDUCATION

 Bachelor of Technology (B. Tech) in Electronics and Communication Engineering from ABES Engineering College, Ghaziabad, India - 2017